<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "SS7_Stack_User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="managing_sccp">
		<title>SCCP Management</title>

		<para>
			SCCP provides connectionless and connection-oriented network services. This includes address(GTT) translation and routing, flow control, segmentation and reassembly.
			A global title is an address (e.g., a dialed 800 number, calling card number, or mobile subscriber identification number) which is translated by SCCP into a destination
			point code and subsystem number. A subsystem number uniquely identifies an application at the destination signaling point. <acronym>SCCP</acronym> is used as the
			transport layer for <acronym>TCAP</acronym>-based services.
		</para>
		<para>
			The first step in configuring SCCP is defining service access points (sap). This step is mandatory. Each SCCP stack can use one or more Mtp3UserPart
			(Refer <xref linkend="configuring_SCCP"/> about Mtp3UserPart settings). A sap is a logical definition of the Mtp3UserPart [corresponding local SPC,
			network indicator (NI) and a set of destinations (remote SPC list)].
		</para>
		<para>
			The second step is the definition of a list of available remote signaling pointcodes (SPC - rsp) and
			a list of available remote Sub-Systems (SNN - rss). This step is also mandatory. If routing only by GlobalTitle is used then it is not required to configure remote Sub-Systems.
		</para>
		<para>
			Since <acronym>SCCP</acronym> acts as a message router, it is required to configure routing information. Rules (rule), primary and backup (address) (if backup addresses are available)
			addresses should be configured. If XUDT and LUDT messages are available in the SS7 network, you should configure a set of long message rules (lmr) that will allow long messages.
			This step is not mandatory. If no long message rules are configured only UDT messages will be used.
		</para>
		<para>
			The last step is optional. You can configure a set of concerned signaling point codes (csp). Each point code will be announced when local SCCP user becomes unavailable.
		</para>

	<section id="managing_sccp_using_CLI">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
		<para>
        	You can manage all SCCP related configurations through the Command Line Interface by using the <literal>sccp</literal> command with appropriate parameters. You can create, modify, delete
        	and view SCCP Service Access Points (sap) and Destinations (dest), Remote Signaling Point Codes (rsp), Remote Sub Systems (rss), Concerned Signaling Point Codes (csp),
        	Routing information (rules, primary and backup addresses) and Long Message Rules (lmr). You can also set and get values for general parameters using this command.
       	</para>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_using_GUI">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
		<para>
			The GUI will allow you to manage your SCCP configurations efficiently using a user-friendly interface. Open a Web Browser and navigate to http://localhost:8080/jss7-management-console/.
			Click on the 'SCCP' link in the left panel. The main panel will display the names of all configured SCCP Management units. To configure or view the settings of a particular SCCP Management
			Unit you must click on the name of that unit. The GUI will look similar to the figure below and is divided into tabs.
		</para>

		<para>
			The first tab will display the properties of the SCCP Management unit. These details displayed here are fetched from the XML descriptor file <filename>jboss-beans.xml</filename>, which is
			located at <filename>$JBOSS_HOME/server/profile_name/deploy/mobicents-ss7-service/META-INF</filename>, where <application>profile_name</application> is the server profile name.
			These properties can be modified here in the GUI. To modify them you must click on pencil, make changes and save. The GUI will then display the modified values.
		</para>
		<figure>
  			<title>GUI - SCCP Management</title>
  			<mediaobject>
    			<imageobject>
      				<imagedata fileref="images/GUI_SCCP_Management.png" format="PNG" align="center"/>
    			</imageobject>
  			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<para>
			The other seven tabs will allow you to manage all SCCP configurations within this SCCP Management unit.
		</para>
	</section>


	<section id="sccp_properties">
		<title>SCCP stack properties</title>


    <section id="sccp_property_sccpprotocolversion">
        <title>SCCP protocol version</title>

            <section id="sccp_property_sccpprotocolversion_CLI">
            <title>Using CLI</title>
                <para>
                    We can specify which protocol specification will use SCCP stack (ITU-T or ANSI).
                </para>
                <para>
                    You can set the 'sccpprotocolversion' by issuing the command <command>sccp set sccpprotocolversion</command> with appropriate parameters as described below.
                    You can verify this by issuing the command <command>sccp get sccpprotocolversion</command> which will display the value set for this property.
                </para>
                <screen><![CDATA[
Name
    sccp set sccpprotocolversion

SYNOPSIS
    sccp set sccpprotocolversion <ITU | ANSI> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
    Sets the value for sccpprotocolversion property ITU or ANSI.
    Default value is ITU.

PARAMETERS

    Optional Parameters

    <stack-name>    -   Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
                    If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
                    will be used.

EXAMPLES
    sccp set sccpprotocolversion ITU
            ]]></screen>
        </section>

        <section id="sccp_property_sccpprotocolversion_min_GUI">
            <title>Using GUI</title>
                <para>On SCCP management page, click on pencil against the 'ReservedForNationalUseValue of AddressIndicator' property and text box becomes editable. Change value and save.</para>
        </section>
    </section>

	<section id="sccp_property_maxdatamessage">
		<title>Maximum Data Message</title>

			<section id="sccp_property_maxdatamessage_CLI">
			<title>Using CLI</title>
				<para>
					You can set the 'maxdatamessage' by issuing the command <command>sccp set maxdatamessage</command> with appropriate parameters as described below.
					You can verify this by issuing the command <command>sccp get maxdatamessage</command> which will display the value set for this property.
				</para>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp set maxdatamessage

SYNOPSIS
	sccp set maxdatamessage <maxdatamessage> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	Sets Max available SCCP message data for all message types. Range is 2560 to 3952.
    If passed value is less than 2560, it sets to 2560 and if passed value is greater
    than 3952, it sets to 3952.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<maxdatamessage>	-	Maximum data message size.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp set maxdatamessage 30000
			]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="sccp_property_maxdatamessage_GUI">
			<title>Using GUI</title>
				<para>On SCCP management page, click on pencil against the 'PreviewMode' property and text box becomes editable. Change value and save. </para>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="sccp_property_periodoflogging">
		<title>Period of logging</title>

			<section id="sccp_property_periodoflogging_CLI">
			<title>Using CLI</title>
				<para>
					You can set the 'periodoflogging' by issuing the command <command>sccp set periodoflogging</command> with appropriate parameters as described below.
					You can verify this by issuing the command <command>sccp get periodoflogging</command> which will display the value set for this property.
				</para>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp set periodoflogging

SYNOPSIS
	sccp set periodoflogging <periodoflogging> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	Sets period of logging warning messages.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<periodoflogging>	-	Period im ms.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp set periodoflogging 10000
			]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="sccp_property_periodoflogging_GUI">
			<title>Using GUI</title>
				<para>On SCCP management page, click on pencil against the 'PeriodOfLogging' property and text box becomes editable. Change value and save. </para>
		</section>
	</section>


	<section id="sccp_property_previewmode">
		<title>Preview Mode</title>

			<section id="sccp_property_previewmode_CLI">
			<title>Using CLI</title>
				<para>
					You can set the 'previewmode' by issuing the command <command>sccp set previewmode</command> with appropriate parameters as described below.
					You can verify this by issuing the command <command>sccp get previewmode</command> which will display the value set for this property.
				</para>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp set previewmode

SYNOPSIS
	sccp set previewmode <true | false> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	If set to true, stack only listens for incoming messages and does not
	send anything out of stack. Messages are silently dropped.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<previewmode>	-	Set preview mode to true or false.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp set previewmode false
			]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="sccp_property_previewmode_GUI">
			<title>Using GUI</title>
				<para>On SCCP management page, click on pencil against the 'PreviewMode' property and text box becomes editable. Change value and save. </para>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="sccp_property_reassemblytimerdelay">
		<title>Reassembly Timer Delay</title>

			<section id="sccp_property_reassemblytimerdelay_CLI">
			<title>Using CLI</title>
				<para>
					You can set the 'reassemblytimerdelay' by issuing the command <command>sccp set reassemblytimerdelay</command> with appropriate parameters as described below.
					You can verify this by issuing the command <command>sccp get reassemblytimerdelay</command> which will display the value set for this property.
				</para>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp set reassemblytimerdelay

SYNOPSIS
	sccp set reassemblytimerdelay <reassemblytimerdelay> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	Sets SCCP segmented message reassembling timeout (in milliseconds).
    Range is 10000 to 20000. If passed value is less than 10000, it sets to 10000 and
    if passed value is greater than 20000, it sets to 20000

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<reassemblytimerdelay>	-	Re-assembly time delay in milliseconds

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp set reassemblytimerdelay 20000
			]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="sccp_property_reassemblytimerdelay_GUI">
			<title>Using GUI</title>
				<para>On SCCP management page, click on pencil against the 'ReassemblyTimerDelay' property and text box becomes editable. Change value and save. </para>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="sccp_property_removespc">
		<title>Remove Signaling Point Code</title>

			<section id="sccp_property_removespc_CLI">
			<title>Using CLI</title>
				<para>
					You can set the 'removespc' by issuing the command <command>sccp set removespc</command> with appropriate parameters as described below.
					You can verify this by issuing the command <command>sccp get removespc</command> which will display the value set for this property.
				</para>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp set removespc

SYNOPSIS
	sccp set removespc <false | true> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	If set, the signaling point code from SCCP called/calling address will
	be removed if corresponding routing is based on GT

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<removespc>	-	true or false value.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp set removespc true
			]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="sccp_property_removespc_GUI">
			<title>Using GUI</title>
				<para>On SCCP management page, click on pencil against the 'RemoveSpc' property and text box becomes editable. Change value and save. </para>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="sccp_property_ssttimerduration_increasefactor">
		<title>SST Timer Duration Increase Factor</title>

			<section id="sccp_property_ssttimerduration_increasefactor_CLI">
			<title>Using CLI</title>
				<para>
					You can set the 'ssttimerduration_increasefactor' by issuing the command <command>sccp set ssttimerduration_increasefactor</command> with appropriate parameters as described below.
					You can verify this by issuing the command <command>sccp get ssttimerduration_increasefactor</command> which will display the value set for this property.
				</para>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp set ssttimerduration_increasefactor

SYNOPSIS
	sccp set ssttimerduration_increasefactor <ssttimerduration_increasefactor>
	stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	Set multiplicator of SST sending interval (next interval will be greater then
	the current by sstTimerDuration_IncreaseFactor). Range is 1 to 4. If passed
	value is less than 1, it sets to 1 and if passed value is greater than 4,
	it sets to 4

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<ssttimerduration_increasefactor>	-	values from 1 to 4 for SST duration increase
										factor.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp set ssttimerduration_increasefactor 1
			]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="sccp_property_ssttimerduration_increasefactor_GUI">
			<title>Using GUI</title>
				<para>On SCCP management page, click on pencil against the 'SstTimerDuration_IncreaseFactor' property and text box becomes editable. Change value and save. </para>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="sccp_property_ssttimerduration_max">
		<title>SST Timer Duration Max</title>

	<section id="sccp_property_ssttimerduration_max_CLI">
			<title>Using CLI</title>
				<para>
					You can set the 'ssttimerduration_max' by issuing the command <command>sccp set ssttimerduration_max</command> with appropriate parameters as described below.
					You can verify this by issuing the command <command>sccp get ssttimerduration_max</command> which will display the value set for this property.
				</para>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp set ssttimerduration_max

SYNOPSIS
	sccp set ssttimerduration_max <ssttimerduration_max> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	Sets Max (after increasing) SST sending interval (in 600000 - 1200000 milliseconds).
	Value can be from 600000 to 1200000. If value passed is less than 600000, it sets to
	600000 and if value passed is greater than 1200000, it sets to 1200000

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<ssttimerduration_max>	-	values from 600000 - 1200000 milliseconds.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp set ssttimerduration_max 600000
			]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="sccp_property_ssttimerduration_max_GUI">
			<title>Using GUI</title>
				<para>On SCCP management page, click on pencil against the 'SstTimerDuration_Max' property and text box becomes editable. Change value and save. </para>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="sccp_property_ssttimerduration_min">
		<title>SST Timer Duration Min</title>

			<section id="sccp_property_ssttimerduration_min_CLI">
			<title>Using CLI</title>
				<para>
					You can set the 'ssttimerduration_min' by issuing the command <command>sccp set ssttimerduration_min</command> with appropriate parameters as described below.
					You can verify this by issuing the command <command>sccp get ssttimerduration_min</command> which will display the value set for this property.
				</para>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp set ssttimerduration_min

SYNOPSIS
	sccp set ssttimerduration_min <ssttimerduration_min> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	Set's min (starting) SST sending interval (in milliseconds). Value can be
	from 5000 to 10000.If value passed is less than 5000, it sets to 5000 and
	if value passed is greater than 10000, its set to 10000

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<ssttimerduration_min>	-	values from 5000 to 10000.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp set ssttimerduration_min 10000
			]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="sccp_property_ssttimerduration_min_GUI">
			<title>Using GUI</title>
				<para>On SCCP management page, click on pencil against the 'SstTimerDuration_Max' property and text box becomes editable. Change value and save. </para>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="sccp_property_zmarginxudtmessage">
		<title>ZMargin XUDT Message</title>

			<section id="sccp_property_zmarginxudtmessage_CLI">
			<title>Using CLI</title>
				<para>
					You can set the 'zmarginxudtmessage' by issuing the command <command>sccp set zmarginxudtmessage</command> with appropriate parameters as described below.
					You can verify this by issuing the command <command>sccp get zmarginxudtmessage</command> which will display the value set for this property.
				</para>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp set ssttimerduration_min

SYNOPSIS
	sccp set zmarginxudtmessage <zmarginxudtmessage> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	Sets segmentation length. If the XUDT message data length greater this value,
    segmentation is processed. Otherwise no segmentation.
    Range is 160 to 255. If passed value is less than 160, it sets to 160 and
    if passed value is greater than 255, it sets to 255.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<zmarginxudtmessage>	-	values from 160 to 255.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp set zmarginxudtmessage 255
			]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="sccp_property_zmarginxudtmessage_min_GUI">
			<title>Using GUI</title>
				<para>On SCCP management page, click on pencil against the 'ZMarginXudtMessage' property and text box becomes editable. Change value and save. </para>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="sccp_property_cc_timer_a">
		<title>Timer A value for the congestion control</title>

			<section id="sccp_property_cc_timer_a_CLI">
			<title>Using CLI</title>
				<para>
					You can set the 'cc_timer_a' by issuing the command <command>sccp set cc_timer_a</command> with appropriate parameters as described below.
					You can verify this by issuing the command <command>sccp get cc_timer_a</command> which will display the value set for this property.
				</para>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp get cc_timer_a

SYNOPSIS
	sccp get cc_timer_a stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	Sets the Timer A value in milliseconds.
	This timer starts at next MTP-STATUS(cong) primitive coming.
	During this timer no more MTP-STATUS(cong) are accepted.

	Default value is 400.
	Possible values are between 60 and 1000.

PARAMETERS

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp set cc_timer_a 400
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="sccp_property_cc_timer_a_GUI">
			<title>Using GUI</title>
				<para>On SCCP management page, click on pencil against the 'Congestion control: Timer A' property and text box becomes editable. Change value and save.</para>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="sccp_property_cc_timer_d">
		<title>Timer D value for the congestion control</title>

			<section id="sccp_property_cc_timer_d_CLI">
			<title>Using CLI</title>
				<para>
					You can set the 'cc_timer_d' by issuing the command <command>sccp set cc_timer_d</command> with appropriate parameters as described below.
					You can verify this by issuing the command <command>sccp get cc_timer_d</command> which will display the value set for this property.
				</para>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp get cc_timer_d

SYNOPSIS
	sccp get cc_timer_d stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	Sets the Timer D value in milliseconds.
	This timer starts after last MTP-STATUS(cong) primitive coming.
	After end of this timer (without new coming MTP-STATUS(cong))
	RSLM (the congestion level) will be reduced.

	Default value is 2000.
	Possible values are between 500 and 10000.

PARAMETERS

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp set cc_timer_d 2000
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="sccp_property_cc_timer_d_min_GUI">
			<title>Using GUI</title>
				<para>On SCCP management page, click on pencil against the 'Congestion control: Timer A' property and text box becomes editable. Change value and save.</para>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="sccp_property_cc_algo">
		<title>Algorithm of the congestion control at SCCP level</title>

			<section id="sccp_property_cc_algo_CLI">
			<title>Using CLI</title>
				<para>
					You can set the 'cc_algo' by issuing the command <command>sccp set cc_algo</command> with appropriate parameters as described below.
					You can verify this by issuing the command <command>sccp get cc_algo</command> which will display the value set for this property.
				</para>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp set cc_algo

SYNOPSIS
	sccp set cc_algo <international | levelDepended> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	Sets the algorithm of the congestion control at SCCP level for outgoing
	messages.
	Possible values are international or levelDepended.
	international algorithm - only one level is provided by MTP3 level
	(in MTP-STATUS primitive). Each MTP-STATUS increases N / M levels.
	international algorithm - MTP3 level (MTP-STATUS primitive) provides
	3 levels of a congestion (1-3) and SCCP congestion will increase to
	the next level after MTP-STATUS next level increase (MTP-STATUS 1
	to N up to 3, MTP-STATUS 2 to N up to 5, MTP-STATUS 3 to N up to 7).

	Default value is international.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<cc_algo>	-	international | levelDepended.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp set cc_algo international
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="sccp_property_cc_algo_GUI">
			<title>Using GUI</title>
				<para>On SCCP management page, click on pencil against the 'Congestion control: algorithm' property and text box becomes editable. Change value and save.</para>
		</section>
	</section>

	<section id="sccp_property_cc_blockingoutgoungsccpmessages">
		<title>Blocking of outgoing messages in case of the congestion</title>

			<section id="sccp_property_blockingoutgoungsccpmessages_CLI">
			<title>Using CLI</title>
				<para>
					You can set the 'cc_blockingoutgoungsccpmessages' by issuing the command <command>sccp set cc_blockingoutgoungsccpmessages</command> with appropriate parameters as described below.
					You can verify this by issuing the command <command>sccp get cc_blockingoutgoungsccpmessages</command> which will display the value set for this property.
				</para>
				<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp set cc_blockingoutgoungsccpmessages

SYNOPSIS
	sccp set cc_blockingoutgoungsccpmessages <false | true> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	Sets the value of if outgoing SCCP messages will be blocked in congestion.
	(depending on message type, UDP messages from level N=6).
	true means that message will be blocken in the congestion case,
	false means not.

	Default value is false.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<cc_blockingoutgoungsccpmessages>	-	false or true.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp set cc_blockingoutgoungsccpmessages false
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="sccp_property_blockingoutgoungsccpmessages_GUI">
			<title>Using GUI</title>
				<para>On SCCP management page, click on pencil against the 'Congestion control: blocking of outgoing messages' property and text box becomes editable. Change value and save.</para>
		</section>
	</section>

</section>


	<section id="managing_sccp_sap_show">
		<title>View all Service Access Points (SAP)</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_sap_show_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can view the details of all configured Service Access Points by issuing the command <command>sccp sap show</command> as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp sap show

SYNOPSIS
	sccp sap show <id> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to view the details of all Service Access Points. If an <id>
	is specified, the command will only display the details of the SAP identified by
	the value of the 'id' specified.

PARAMETERS

	Optional Parameters

	<id>			-	The id of the SAP whose details are to be displayed. If
					this parameter is not specified, the details of all
					defined SAPs will be displayed.

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_sap_show_GUI">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
<para>Navigate to the specific SCCP Management unit and switch to the 'SAP' tab. Here you can view a list of all the Service Access Points created. Every correctly configured Service Access Point will be displayed in a row with their defined values. The last column 'Action' will allow you to delete the Service Access Point.
</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_sap_create">
		<title>Create a new Service Access Point</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_sap_create_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can create a new Service Access Point by issuing the command <command>sccp sap create</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp sap create

SYNOPSIS
	sccp sap create <id> <mtp3-id> <opc> <ni> stackname <stack-name> networkid <networkId>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to define a new Service Access Point.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>			-	The newly defined SAP will be identified using this 'id'.
					This must be a unique number.

	<mtp3-id>		-	Mtp3UserPart index - used as an index of 'mtp3UserPart'
					property of the SccpStack Bean. For each Mtp3UserPart,
					a sap must be configured.

	<opc>			-	MTP Point code of the local signaling point. Takes an
					Integer Value.

	<ni>			-	Network indicator that forms part of the
					Service Information Octet (SIO).

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

    <networkId>     - A digital parameter that means to which virtual SS7 network
                    belongs Service Access Point (SAP). If this parameter is
                    skipped - networkId will be set to "0" when SAP creation.
                    Refer <xref linkend="design_multitenancy"/>.


EXAMPLES
	sccp sap create 1 1 101 2

	The above command will create a new Service Access Point identified by the
	number '1'. The values for 'mtp3-id', 'opc' and 'ni' are 1, 101 and 2 respectively.
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_sap_create_gui">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
			<procedure>
				<title>Create a new Service Access Point using GUI</title>
				<step><para>Navigate to the 'SAP' tab in the SCCP Management window and click on the 'Create SAP' button. This will launch a pop-up 'Create SAP'.</para></step>
				<step><para>In the 'Create SAP' pop-up, add details of the new Service Access Point. You must ensure that you fill in all the mandatory parameters (Id, MTP3 Id, OPC, NI). For definition of these parameters, please refer to the description of the CLI command for the same in the preceding section.
				</para></step>
				<step><para>Verify the details entered and then click on the 'Create' button. A new SAP will be created with parameters as specified. If there is an error in creating the SAP then you will find the details of the error in the Management Console Log section below.</para></step>
				<step><para>Click on the 'Close' button to close the 'Create SAP' pop-up.
				</para></step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_sap_modify">
		<title>Modify a Service Access Point</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_sap_modify_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can modify the values of a Service Access Point by issuing the command <command>sccp sap modify</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp sap modify

SYNOPSIS
	sccp sap modify <id> <mtp3-id> <opc> <ni> stackname <stack-name> networkid <networkId>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to modify a previously defined Service Access Point.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>			-	The id of the SAP whose values are being modified.

	<mtp3-id>		-	Mtp3UserPart index - used as an index of 'mtp3UserPart'
					property of the SccpStack Bean. For each Mtp3UserPart, a
					sap must be configured.

	<opc>			-	MTP Point code of the local signaling point. Takes an
					Integer Value.

	<ni>			-	Network indicator that forms part of the Service
					Information Octet (SIO).

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

    <networkId>     - A digital parameter that means to which virtual SS7 network
                    belongs Service Access Point (SAP). If this parameter is
                    skipped - networkId will be set to "0" when SAP creation.
                    Refer <xref linkend="design_multitenancy"/>.


EXAMPLES
	sccp sap modify 1 2 102 2

	The above command will modify the values of the Service Access Point identified
	by the number '1'. The new values for 'mtp3-id', 'opc' and 'ni' are 2, 102 and 2
	respectively.
]]></screen>
		</section><!--
		<section id="managing_sccp_sap_modify_gui">
		<title></title>
		</section>-->
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_sap_delete">
		<title>Delete a Service Access Point</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_sap_delete_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can delete a SAP by issuing the command <command>sccp sap delete</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp sap delete

SYNOPSIS
	sccp sap delete <id> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to delete a previously defined Service Access Point.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>			-	The id of the SAP that is being deleted.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp sap delete 1

	The above command will delete the SAP identified by the number '1'.
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_sap_delete_gui">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
			<procedure>
				<title>Delete a SAP using GUI</title>
				<step><para>Navigate to the 'SAP' tab in the SCCP Management Unit window and locate the row corresponding to the SAP you wish to delete.</para></step>
				<step><para>The last column for 'Delete' action will display a 'x' button in red and will be enabled.</para></step>
				<step><para>Click on the red 'x' button to delete the corresponding SAP.
				</para></step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	</section>

<section id="managing_sccp_dest_show">
		<title>View all Destinations specified for a SAP</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_dest_show_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can view the details of all Destinations specified for a
	Service Access Point by issuing the command <command>sccp dest show</command> as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp dest show

SYNOPSIS
	sccp dest show <sap-id> <id> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to view the details of all Destinations specified for a
	Service Access Point. If an <id> is specified in the command, it will only display
	the details of the Destination identified by the value of the 'id' specified.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<sap-id>	-	The id of the SAP whose Destination details are to be
				displayed.


	Optional Parameters

	<id>			-	The id of the Destination whose details are to be
					displayed. If this parameter is not specified, the details
					of all Destinations defined within the SAP 'sap-id' will
					be displayed.

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_dest_show_GUI">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
<para>Navigate to the specific SCCP Management unit and switch to the 'SAP' tab. Here you can view a list of all the Service Access Points created. Every correctly configured Service Access Point will be displayed in a row with their defined values. To view the Destination details of a specific SAP, click on the row corresponding to the SAP. The row will expand below to display the details of all configured Destinations.
</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_dest_create">
		<title>Define a new Destination for a SAP</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_dest_create_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can define a new Destination for a Service Access Point by issuing the command <command>sccp dest create</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp dest create

SYNOPSIS
	sccp dest create <sap-id> <id> <first-dpc> <last-dpc> <first-sls> <last-sls>
	<sls-mask> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to define a new Destination for a Service Access Point.
	For every SAP in the system, you should configure one or more Destinations.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<sap-id>	-	The identifier of the SAP for which this new Destination
				is being defined. You must ensure that the SAP has been
				created prior to issuing this command.

	<id>		-	An identifier for this newly created Destination.
				The number must be unique within each SAP.

	<first-dpc>	-	The first value of the remote signaling point codes range.

	<last-dpc>	-	The last value of the remote signaling point codes range.
				If the Destination specifies only a single Signaling
				Point Code, this value must be equal to the value
				specified for 'first-dpc'.

	<first-sls>	-	The first value of the SLS range.
				SLS value range is from 0 to 255.

	<last-sls>	-	The last value of the SLS range.

	<sls-mask>	-	The mask value. SLS of a message will be exposed by
				performing a bitwise AND operation with this mask prior to
				comparing it with first-sls and last-sls values.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.


EXAMPLES
	sccp dest create 1 1 201 201 0 7 7

	The above command will create a new Destination (identified by number '1') for
	a Service Access Point identified by the number '1'. The values for 'first-dpc',
	'last-dpc', 'first-sls', 'last-sls' and 'sls-mask' are 201, 201, 0, 7 and 7
	respectively.

	sccp dest create 2 1 300 399 0 255 255

	The above command will create a new Destination (identified by number '2') for
	a Service Access Point identified by the number '1'. The values for 'first-dpc',
	'last-dpc', 'first-sls', 'last-sls' and 'sls-mask' are 300, 399, 0, 255 and 255
	respectively. This Destination will cover all possible SLS values.
	Therefore the value for first-sls =0, last-sls=255 and sls-mask=255
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_dest_create_gui">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
			<procedure>
				<title>Define a new Destination for a Service Access Point using GUI</title>
				<step><para>Navigate to the 'SAP' tab in the SCCP Management window and click on the row corresponding to the SAP for which you would like to define a new Destination.
				</para></step>
				<step><para>The SAP row will expand below to display the details of all configured Destinations. In this section for Destinations, click on the 'Create Destination' button. This will launch a new pop-up 'Create MTP3 Destination'.</para></step>
				<step><para>In the 'Create MTP3 Destination' pop-up, add details of the new Destination being defined for the Service Access Point. You must ensure that you fill in all the mandatory parameters. For definition of these parameters, please refer to the description of the CLI command for the same in the preceding section.
				</para></step>
				<step><para>Verify the details entered and then click on the 'Create' button. A new Destination will be created with parameters as specified. If there is an error in creating the SAP then you will find the details of the error in the Management Console Log section below.</para></step>
				<step><para>Click on the 'Close' button to close the 'Create MTP3 Destination' pop-up.
				</para></step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_dest_modify">
		<title>Modify a Destination defined for a SAP</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_dest_modify_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can modify the values of a Destination defined for a Service Access Point by issuing the command <command>sccp dest modify</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp dest modify

SYNOPSIS
	sccp dest modify <sap-id> <id> <first-dpc> <last-dpc> <first-sls> <last-sls>
	<sls-mask> stackname <stack-name>


DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to modify the values of a Destination previously defined for
	a Service Access Point.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<sap-id>	-	The identifier of the SAP whose Destination is being
				modified.

	<id>		-	The identifier of the Destination that is being modified.

	<first-dpc>	-	The first value of the remote signaling point codes range.

	<last-dpc>	-	The last value of the remote signaling point codes range.
				If the Destination specifies only a single Signaling
				Point Code, this value must be equal to the value
				specified for 'first-dpc'.

	<first-sls>	-	The first value of the SLS range.
				SLS value range is from 0 to 255.

	<last-sls>	-	The last value of the SLS range.

	<sls-mask>	-	The mask value. SLS of a message will be exposed by
				performing a bitwise AND operation with this mask prior to
				comparing it with first-sls and last-sls values.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp dest modify 1 1 201 299 0 255 255

	The above command will modify the values of the Destination identified by the
	number '1' within the Service Access Point identified by the number '1'.
	The new values for 'first-dpc', 'last-dpc', 'first-sls', 'last-sls' and 'sls-mask'
	are 201, 299, 0, 255 and 255 respectively.
]]></screen>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_dest_delete">
		<title>Delete a Destination defined for a SAP</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_dest_delete_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can delete a Destination defined for a SAP by issuing the command <command>sccp dest delete</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp dest delete

SYNOPSIS
	sccp dest delete <sap-id> <id> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to remove a previously defined Destination from a
	Service Access Point.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<sap-id>	-	The identifier of the SAP whose Destination is being
				deleted.

	<id>		-	The identifier of the Destination that is being
				deleted.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp dest delete 1 1

	The above command will delete the Destination identified by the number '1' from
	the SAP identified by the number '1'.
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_dest_delete_gui">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
			<procedure>
				<title>Delete a Destination defined for a SAP using GUI</title>
				<step><para>Navigate to the 'SAP' tab in the SCCP Management Unit window and click on the row corresponding to the SAP from which you wish to delete a Destination.</para></step>
				<step><para>The SAP row will expand below to display the details of all configured Destinations. In this section for Destinations, locate the specific Destination you wish to remove from the list.</para></step>
				<step><para>In the row corresponding to the identified Destination, click on the red 'x' button in the actions column to delete that Destination.</para></step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	</section>


<section id="managing_sccp_addr_show">
		<title>View all configured SCCP Addresses</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_addr_show_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can view the details of all configured SCCP Addresses by issuing the command <command>sccp address show</command> as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp address show

SYNOPSIS
	sccp address show <id> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to view the details of all configured addresses.
	If an <id> is specified in the command, it will only display the details of the
	Address identified by the value of the 'id' specified.

PARAMETERS

	Optional Parameters

	<id>			-	The id of the Address whose details are to be displayed.
					If this parameter is not specified, the details of all
					configured Addresses will be displayed.

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_addr_show_GUI">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
<para>Navigate to the specific SCCP Management unit and switch to the 'Address' tab. Here you can view a list of all the configured Addresses. Every correctly configured Address will be displayed in a row along with the defined values.
</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_addr_create">
		<title>Create a new Primary/Backup address</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_addr_create_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can create a new primary address or backup address of translation by issuing the command <command>sccp address create</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp address create

SYNOPSIS
	sccp address create <id> <address-indicator> <point-code> <subsystem-number>
	<translation-type> <numbering-plan> <nature-of-address-indicator> <digits>
	stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to create a new primary address or backup address of
	translation. You can create a new newCallingParty address as well
	using this command. The global title address information of this command is combined with
	the global title being translated by examining the mask provided in the
	'sccp rule create' command.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>			-	A unique number to identify this address.

	<address-indicator>	-	The address indicator is the first field in a SCCP
					Party Address (called/calling) and is one octet in
					length. Its function is to indicate which
					information elements are present so that the
					address can be interpreted. In other words, it
					indicates the type of addressing information that
					is to be found in the address field. The
					addressing information from the original global
					title is then compared with the passed address
					information to match the rule.

					SCCP ADDRESS INDICATOR
					--------------------------------
					| 8 | 7 | 6 | 5 | 4 |3 | 2 | 1 |
					--------------------------------

					Bit '1'     : PC Indicator
						      (1 = included)

					Bit '2'     : SSN Indicator
						      (1 = included)

					Bit '3 - 6' : GT Indicator
						      (0000 = GT not included)
						      (0001 = GT includes
							      Nature of Address)
						      (0010 = GT includes
							      Translation Type)
						      (0011 = GT includes
							      Translation Type,
							      Numbering Plan and
							      Encoding Scheme)
						      (0100 = GT includes
							      Translation Type,
							      Numbering Plan and
							      Encoding Scheme and
							      Nature of Address)

					Bit '7'     : Routing Indicator
						      (0 = Route on GT,
						      1 = Route on PC + SSN)

					Bit '8'     : Reserved for National use.

					Only two fields of Address Indicator is used now for GTT:
                    - GT Indicator (this is used for GlobalTitle type that
                      will be created)
                    - Routing Indicator bit (0 = Route on GT, 1 = Route on
                      PC + SSN)
                    GT Indicator for ITU-T network that is mostly used is -
                    0100 (GT includes Translation Type, Numbering Plan and
                    Encoding Scheme and Nature of Address). Digital value
                    for it is - 16.
                    For 0100 GT Indicator we will use two possible values:
                    16 - 0100 GT Indicator and Route on GT
                    80 - 0100 GT Indicator and Route on PC + SSN
                    Even when SCCP stack works in ANSI mode Address Indicator
                    value for CLI and GUI must have values that we use for
                    ITU-T mode.

	<point-code>		-	MTP Signaling Point Code.
					This parameter contains a point code to which message will
					be routed after GTT (DPC field).
					This parameter is mandatory.

	<subsystem-number>	- This parameter contains SSN which will be placed
	                into CalledPartyAddress. If you set this parameter to "0",
	                SSN from CalledPartyAddress of an original message will be
	                put into CalledPartyAddress.

	<translation-type>	-	This is ignored if GT Indicator is 0000 or 0001.

					TRANSLATION TYPE VALUES

					Value		Description
					----------------------------------
					0		Unknown

					1  - 63		International Service

					64 - 127	Spare

					128 - 254	National Network Specific

					255		Reserved for Expansion

					Value of this parameter will be placed into
					CalledPartyAddress. This parameter is mandatory if GT
					Indicator suppose this parameter is included into GT.
					Most used value: 0 - translation-type - Unknown

	<numbering-plan>	-	The Number Plan (NP) field specifies the numbering
					plan which the address information follows. This
					is ignored if GT Indicator is 0000, 0001 or 0010.

                    Value of this parameter will be placed into
                    CalledPartyAddress. This parameter is mandatory if GT
                    Indicator suppose this parameter is included into GT.
                    Most used value: 1 - numbering-plan - ISDN/telephony

	<nature-of-address>	-	The Nature of Address Indicator (NAI) field
					defines the address range for a specific numbering
					plan. This is only used if GT Indicator is 0100.

                    Value of this parameter will be placed into
                    CalledPartyAddress. This parameter is mandatory if GT
                    Indicator suppose this parameter is included into GT.
                    Most used value: 4 - nature-of-address - International

	<digits>		-	The global title address information to translate
					to. Specified as string of digits divided into
					subsections using separator '/' depending on if
					the mask contains separator or not.
					The digits string can contain:

					DIGIT PATTERN

					Value		Description
					----------------------------------
					-		padding - ignored

					/		separator used to split the digit
							pattern into sections.
							Each section is processed
							differently as specified by the
							mask parameter in the
							'sccp rule create' command.

                    We need this parameter if at least one section of Rule
                    mask contains "R" (replace) value. Else set this field
                    to "0". If this field is needed it should contain the
                    same subsections as the rule mask has.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp address create 1 71 2 8 0 0 3 123456789

]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_addr_create_gui">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
			<procedure>
				<title>Create a new Primary/Backup Address using GUI</title>
				<step><para>Navigate to the 'Address' tab in the SCCP Management window and click on the 'Create Address' button. This will launch a new pop-up 'Create SCCP Address'.
				</para></step>
				<step><para>In the 'Create SCCP Address' pop-up, add details of the new SCCP Address being defined. You must ensure that you fill in all the mandatory parameters. For definition of these parameters, please refer to the description of the CLI command for the same in the preceding section.
				</para></step>
				<step><para>Verify the details entered and then click on the 'Create' button. A new Address will be created with parameters as specified. If there is an error in creating the Address then you will find the details of the error in the Management Console Log section below.</para></step>
				<step><para>Click on the 'Close' button to close the 'Create SCCP Address' pop-up.
				</para></step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_addr_modify">
		<title>Modify a Primary/Backup Address</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_addr_modify_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can modify the values of a primary address or backup address of translation by issuing the command <command>sccp address modify</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp address modify

SYNOPSIS
	sccp address modify <id> <address-indicator> <point-code> <subsystem-number>
	<translation-type> <numbering-plan> <nature-of-address-indicator> <digits>
	stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to modify the values of an address
	previously defined.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>			-	Identifier of the address to be modified.

	<address-indicator>	-	The address indicator is the first field in a SCCP
					Party Address (called/calling) and is one octet in
					length. Its function is to indicate which
					information elements are present so that the
					address can be interpreted. In other words, it
					indicates the type of addressing information that
					is to be found in the address field. The
					addressing information from the original global
					title is then compared with the passed address
					information to match the rule.

					SCCP ADDRESS INDICATOR
					--------------------------------
					| 8 | 7 | 6 | 5 | 4 |3 | 2 | 1 |
					--------------------------------

					Bit '1'     : PC Indicator
						      (1 = included)

					Bit '2'     : SSN Indicator
						      (1 = included)

					Bit '3 - 6' : GT Indicator
						      (0000 = GT not included)
						      (0001 = GT includes
							      Nature of Address)
						      (0010 = GT includes
							      Translation Type)
						      (0011 = GT includes
							      Translation Type,
							      Numbering Plan and
							      Encoding Scheme)
						      (0100 = GT includes
							      Translation Type,
							      Numbering Plan and
							      Encoding Scheme and
							      Nature of Address)

					Bit '7'     : Routing Indicator
						      (0 = Route on GT,
						      1 = Route on PC + SSN)

					Bit '8'     : Reserved for National use.

                    Only two fields of Address Indicator is used now for GTT:
                    - GT Indicator (this is used for GlobalTitle type that
                      will be created)
                    - Routing Indicator bit (0 = Route on GT, 1 = Route on
                      PC + SSN)
                    GT Indicator for ITU-T network that is mostly used is -
                    0100 (GT includes Translation Type, Numbering Plan and
                    Encoding Scheme and Nature of Address). Digital value
                    for it is - 16.
                    For 0100 GT Indicator we will use two possible values:
                    16 - 0100 GT Indicator and Route on GT
                    80 - 0100 GT Indicator and Route on PC + SSN
                    Even when SCCP stack works in ANSI mode Address Indicator
                    value for CLI and GUI must have values that we use for
                    ITU-T mode.

    <point-code>        -   MTP Signaling Point Code.
                    This parameter contains a point code to which message will
                    be routed after GTT (DPC field).
                    This parameter is mandatory.

    <subsystem-number>  - This parameter contains SSN which will be placed
                    into CalledPartyAddress. If you set this parameter to "0",
                    SSN from CalledPartyAddress of an original message will be
                    put into CalledPartyAddress.

	<translation-type>	-	This is ignored if GT Indicator is 0000 or 0001.

					TRANSLATION TYPE VALUES

					Value		Description
					----------------------------------
					0		Unknown

					1  - 63		International Service

					64 - 127	Spare

					128 - 254	National Network Specific

					255		Reserved for Expansion

                    Value of this parameter will be placed into
                    CalledPartyAddress. This parameter is mandatory if GT
                    Indicator suppose this parameter is included into GT.
                    Most used value: 0 - translation-type - Unknown

    <numbering-plan>    -   The Number Plan (NP) field specifies the numbering
                    plan which the address information follows. This
                    is ignored if GT Indicator is 0000, 0001 or 0010.

                    Value of this parameter will be placed into
                    CalledPartyAddress. This parameter is mandatory if GT
                    Indicator suppose this parameter is included into GT.
                    Most used value: 1 - numbering-plan - ISDN/telephony

    <nature-of-address> -   The Nature of Address Indicator (NAI) field
                    defines the address range for a specific numbering
                    plan. This is only used if GT Indicator is 0100.

                    Value of this parameter will be placed into
                    CalledPartyAddress. This parameter is mandatory if GT
                    Indicator suppose this parameter is included into GT.
                    Most used value: 4 - nature-of-address - International

	<digits>		-	The global title address information to translate
					to. Specified as string of digits divided into
					subsections using separator '/' depending on if
					the mask contains separator or not.
					The digits string can contain:

					DIGIT PATTERN

					Value		Description
					----------------------------------
					-		padding - ignored

					/		separator used to split the digit
							pattern into sections.
							Each section is processed
							differently as specified by the
							mask parameter in the
							'sccp rule create' command.

                    We need this parameter if at least one section of Rule
                    mask contains "R" (replace) value. Else set this field
                    to "0". If this field is needed it should contain the
                    same subsections as the rule mask has.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.
]]></screen>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_addr_delete">
		<title>Delete a Primary/Backup Address</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_addr_delete_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can delete a Primary or Backup Address by issuing the command <command>sccp address delete</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp address delete

SYNOPSIS
	sccp address delete <id> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to remove previously defined addresses.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>		-	The identifier of the address that is being deleted.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp address delete 1

	The above command will delete the address identified by the number '1'.
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_addr_delete_gui">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
			<procedure>
				<title>Delete a Primary/Backup Address using GUI</title>
				<step><para>Navigate to the 'Address' tab in the SCCP Management Unit window and locate the row corresponding to the Address you wish to delete.</para></step>
				<step><para>In the row corresponding to the identified Address, click on the red 'x' button in the actions column to delete that Address.</para></step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	</section>

<section id="managing_sccp_rule_show">
		<title>View all configured SCCP Rules</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rule_show_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can view the details of all configured SCCP Rules by issuing the command <command>sccp rule show</command> as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp rule show

SYNOPSIS
	sccp rule show <id> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to view the details of all Rules configured. If an <id> is
	specified in the command, it will only display the details of the Rule identified
	by the value of the 'id' specified.

PARAMETERS

	Optional Parameters

	<id>		-	The id of the Rule whose details are to be displayed.
				If this parameter is not specified, the details of all
				configured Rules will be displayed.

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
			If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
			will be used.
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rule_show_GUI">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
<para>Navigate to the specific SCCP Management unit and switch to the 'Rules' tab. Here you can view a list of all the configured Rules. Every correctly configured Rule will be displayed in a row along with the defined values.
</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_rule_create">
		<title>Create a new SCCP Rule</title>
		<section id="sorting_algorithm">
		<title>Sorting Algorithm</title>
			<para>
				When you define Rules, a comparison function imposes ordering the collection of SCCP Rules using a sorting algorithm that is based on the GT digits. The algorithm is defined below:
				<orderedlist>
				<listitem><para>Rules defined with OriginationType==localOriginated or OriginationType==remoteOriginated, are always at the top of the list. Rules defined with OriginationType==All are always at the bottom of the list.</para> <para>Among rules with the same values for OriginationType (All or localOriginated/remoteOriginated), the sorting is done using the below rules. </para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>Rules with GT digits having no wildcard (* or ?) are always at the top of the list. Between
 two Rules with GT digits, both having no wildcards, the one with the shortest length is at the top
 of the list. For example, Digit1 "123456" will be above Digit2 "1234567890" and this will be above Digit3 "999/*</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>Rules with GT digits having the wildcard "?" are always above digits having the wildcard "*". For
 example, Digit1 "800/????/9" will be above Digit2 "999/*</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para>Between Rules with two GT digits both having wildcard "?", the one with the least number of
 wildcard "?" is at the top of the list. For example, Digit1 "800/????/9" will be above Digit2
 "800/?????/9"</para></listitem>
				<listitem><para> Between Rules with two GT digits both having an equal number of wildcard "?", the digit whose
 first appearance of "?" is after other, is at the top of the list. For example between
 Digit1 "80/??/0/???/9" and Digit 2 "800/?????/9", Digit2 is above Digit1.</para></listitem>
				</orderedlist>
				When a Rule is compared during Translation, comparison always starts from the top of the list.
			</para>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rule_create_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can create a new Rule by issuing the command <command>sccp rule create</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp rule create

SYNOPSIS
	sccp rule create <id> <mask> <address-indicator> <point-code> <subsystem-number>
	<translation-type> <numbering-plan> <nature-of-address-indicator> <digits>
	<ruleType> <primary-address-id> backup-addressid <backup-address-id>
	loadsharing-algo <loadsharing-algorithm> newcgparty-addressid
	<new-callingPartyAddress-id> origination-type <originationType>
	stackname <stack-name> networkid <networkId>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to create a new SCCP Routing Rule. You must ensure that
	primary and backup addresses are configured properly prior to executing this
	command.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>			-	A unique number to identify this Rule.

	<mask>			-	A mask defines which part of the originally dialed
					digits remains in the translated digits and which
					part is replaced by the digits from primary or
					backup address. A mask is divided into sections by
					separator '/'. The number of sections in a mask
					should be equal to the sections in digits passed
					in this command and the sections in primary or
					backup address. This paramter is mandatory.

					MASK DEFINITIONS

					Mnemonic	Function
					----------------------------------
					- 		Ignore

					/		Separator used to split the mask
							into sections.

					K		Retain the original dialed digits
							of this section in the translated
							digits.

					R		Replace the original dialed digits
							of this section with the same
							section from primary or backup
							address in the translated digits.

	<address-indicator>	-	The address indicator is the first field in a SCCP
					Party Address (called/calling) and is one octet in
					length. Its function is to indicate which
					information elements are present so that the
					address can be interpreted. In other words, it
					indicates the type of addressing information that
					is to be found in the address field. The
					addressing information from the original global
					title is then compared with the passed address
					information to match the rule.

					SCCP ADDRESS INDICATOR
					--------------------------------
					| 8 | 7 | 6 | 5 | 4 |3 | 2 | 1 |
					--------------------------------

					Bit '1'     : PC Indicator
						      (1 = included)

					Bit '2'     : SSN Indicator
						      (1 = included)

					Bit '3 - 6' : GT Indicator
						      (0000 = GT not included)
						      (0001 = GT includes
							      Nature of Address)
						      (0010 = GT includes
							      Translation Type)
						      (0011 = GT includes
							      Translation Type,
							      Numbering Plan and
							      Encoding Scheme)
						      (0100 = GT includes
							      Translation Type,
							      Numbering Plan and
							      Encoding Scheme and
							      Nature of Address)

					Bit '7'     : Routing Indicator
						      (0 = Route on GT,
						      1 = Route on PC + SSN)

					Bit '8'     : Reserved for National use.

					Only GT Indicator is used in the current implementation.
					A Rule matches to an original address only if GT Indicator
					from address-indicator is the same in a rule and in an
					original address. GT Indicator for ITU-T network that is
					mostly used is - 0100 (GT includes Translation Type,
					Numbering Plan and Encoding Scheme and Nature of Address).
					If you also use 0100 - use digital value for it - 16.
                    Even when SCCP stack works in ANSI mode Address Indicator
                    value for CLI and GUI must have values that we use for
                    ITU-T mode.

	<point-code>		-	MTP Signaling Point Code. This is ignored if
					Bit '0' of address-indicator is not set.
					This parameter is not used in currentimplemetation and
					can be set to "0".

	<subsystem-number>	-	This is ignored if Bit '1' of address-indicator is
					not set.
                    This parameter is not used in currentimplemetation and
                    can be set to "0".

	<translation-type>	-	This is ignored if GT Indicator is 0000 or 0001.

					TRANSLATION TYPE VALUES

					Value		Description
					----------------------------------
					0		Unknown

					1  - 63		International Service

					64 - 127	Spare

					128 - 254	National Network Specific

					255		Reserved for Expansion

					This paramter is mandatory.
					A Rule matches to an original address only if a value of
					this parameter is the same in a rule and in an original
					address. Values are compared only if GT type contains this
					parameter (see GT Indicator description in
					<address-indicator> parameter).
					Most used values:
					0 - translation-type - Unknown

	<numbering-plan>	-	The Number Plan (NP) field specifies the numbering
					plan which the address information follows. This
					is ignored if GT Indicator is 0000, 0001 or 0010.

					NUMBER PLAN VALUES

					Value		Description
					----------------------------------
					0		Unknown

					1		ISDN/Telephony Number Plan
							(Recommendations E.163 and E.164)

					2		Generic Numbering Plan

					3		Data Numbering Plan
							(Recommendations X.121)

					4		Telex Numbering Plan
							(Recommendations F.69)

					5		Maritime Mobile Numbering Plan
							(Recommendations E.210, E.211)

					6		Land Mobile Numbering Plan
							(Recommendations E.212)

					7		ISDN/Mobile Numbering Plan
							(Recommendations E.214)

					8 to 13		Spare

					14		Private Network or
							Network-Specific Numbering Plan

					15		Reserved

                    This paramter is mandatory.
                    A Rule matches to an original address only if a value of
                    this parameter is the same in a rule and in an original
                    address. Values are compared only if GT type contains this
                    parameter (see GT Indicator description in
                    <address-indicator> parameter).
                    Most used values:
                    1 - numbering-plan - ISDN/telephony

	<nature-of-address>	-	The Nature of Address Indicator (NAI) field
					defines the address range for a specific numbering
					plan. This is only used if GT Indicator is 0100.

					NAI VALUES

					Value		Description
					----------------------------------
					0		Unknown

					1		Subscriber Number

					2		Reserved for National use

					3		National Significant Number

					4		International Number

					5 to 127	Spare

                    This paramter is mandatory.
                    A Rule matches to an original address only if a value of
                    this parameter is the same in a rule and in an original
                    address. Values are compared only if GT type contains this
                    parameter (see GT Indicator description in
                    <address-indicator> parameter).
                    Most used values:
                    4 - nature-of-address - International

	<digits>		-	Specifies the string of digits divided into
					subsections using separator '/' depending on if
					the mask contains separator or not. The dialed
					digits should match with theses digits as per the
					rule specified below:

					DIGIT PATTERN

					Value		Description
					----------------------------------
					-		padding - ignored

					*		wildcard - matches any number of
							digits

					?		wildcard - matches exactly one
							digit

					/		separator used to split the digit
							pattern into sections.
							Each section can be processed
							differently as specified
							by the mask parameter.

					This parameter is mandatory. It should contain the same
					subsections count as the rule mask has.

	<ruleType>		-	Takes one of the following values defined below.

					RULE TYPE VALUES

					Value		Description
					----------------------------------
					solitary	Only one (primary) address is used
							for routing.
							(<backup-address-id> may be missed
							in this case).

					dominant	Both primary and backup
							addresses are used and mandatory.
							If both the addresses are
							available, the primary address is
							used for routing.

					loadshared	Both primary and backup
							addresses are used and mandatory.
							If both the addresses are
							available, either primary or
							backup address is used for
							routing.
							The <loadsharing-algorithm> should
							be configured in this case.

					broadcast	Both primary and backup addresses
							are used and are mandatory. All
							messages are routed to both
							addresses.

	<primary-address-id>	-	Identifies the SCCP Address used as the primary
					translation.

	Optional Parameters

	<backup-address-id>	-	Identifies the SCCP Address used as the backup
					translation in case the pointcode specified by the
					primary address is not available. Backup address
					is used if <ruleType> is not "solitary".

	<loadsharing-algorithm>	-	This parameter is mandatory if <ruleType> is
					"loadshared". The Loadsharing algorithm is
					configured here. Possible values of the parameter
					are:

					LOAD SHARING ALGORITHM VALUES

					Value		Description
					----------------------------------
					bit4 		if( (SLS & 0x10) == 0 )
							<route to primary> else
							<route to backup>

							This algorithm is the best if all
							traffic is local (mobicents stack)
							originated

					bit3		if( (SLS & 0x08) == 0 )
							<route to primary> else
							<route to backup>
							This algorithm can be used if not
							all traffic is local
							(mobicents stack) originated.
							But only 8 links are acceptable in
							both linksets.

					bit2		if( (SLS & 0x04) == 0 )
							<route to primary> else
							<route to backup>
							This algorithm can be used if not
							all traffic is local
							(mobicents stack) originated.
							But only 8 links are acceptable in
							both linksets.

					bit1		if( (SLS & 0x02) == 0 )
							<route to primary> else
							<route to backup>
							This algorithm can be used if not
							all traffic is local
							(mobicents stack) originated.
							But only 8 links are acceptable in
							both linksets.

					bit0		if( (SLS & 0x01) == 0 )
							<route to primary> else
							<route to backup>
							This algorithm can be used if not
							all traffic is local
							(mobicents stack) originated.
							But only 8 links are acceptable in
							both linksets.


	<new-callingPartyAddress-id>
				-	This address will replace the
					callingPartyAddresses of messages that fit a Rule.

	<originationType>	-	Takes one of the following values defined below.
					If the parameter is not defined, rule applies to
					all messages regardless of their origination.

					ORIGINATION TYPE VALUES

					Value			Description
					-------------------------------------
					localOriginated		If this parameter is
								"localOriginated", then a
								rule applies only for
								messages originating from
								local SCCP users
								(for example a local
								TCAP stack).

					remoteOriginated	If this parameter is
								"remoteOriginated", then a
								rule applies only for
								messages originating from
								SS7 network and not for
								messages originating from
								local SCCP users.

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

    <networkId>     - A digital parameter that means to which virtual SS7 network
                    belongs a Rule. If this parameter is skipped - networkId will
                    be set to "0" when a Rule creation.
                    Refer <xref linkend="design_multitenancy"/>.

EXAMPLES
	sccp rule create 1 R 71 2 8 0 0 3 123456789 solitary 1

	sccp rule create 2 R 71 2 8 0 0 3 123456789 dominant 1 1

	sccp rule create 2 R 71 2 8 0 0 3 123456789 loadshared 1 1 bit4
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rule_create_gui">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
			<procedure>
				<title>Create a new Rule using GUI</title>
				<step><para>Navigate to the 'Rules' tab in the SCCP Management window and click on the 'Create Rule' button. This will launch a new pop-up 'Create Rule'.
				</para></step>
				<step><para>In the 'Create Rule' pop-up, add details of the new SCCP Rule being defined. You must ensure that you fill in all the mandatory parameters. For definition of these parameters, please refer to the description of the CLI command for the same in the preceding section.
				</para></step>
				<step><para>Verify the details entered and then click on the 'Create' button. A new Rule will be created with parameters as specified. If there is an error in creating the Rule then you will find the details of the error in the Management Console Log section below.</para></step>
				<step><para>Click on the 'Close' button to close the 'Create Rule' pop-up.
				</para></step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_rule_modify">
		<title>Modify a SCCP Rule</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rule_modify_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can modify the values of a Rule by issuing the command <command>sccp rule modify</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp rule modify

SYNOPSIS
	sccp rule modify <id> <mask> <address-indicator> <point-code> <subsystem-number>
	<translation-type> <numbering-plan> <nature-of-address-indicator> <digits>
	<ruleType> <primary-address-id> backup-addressid <backup-address-id>
	loadsharing-algo <loadsharing-algorithm> newcgparty-addressid
	<new-callingPartyAddress-id> origination-type <originationType>
	stackname <stack-name> networkid <networkId>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to modify the values of a SCCP Route previously defined.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>			-	A unique number to identify this Rule.

	<mask>			-	A mask defines which part of the originally dialed
					digits remains in the translated digits and which
					part is replaced by the digits from primary or
					backup address. A mask is divided into sections by
					separator '/'. The number of sections in a mask
					should be equal to the sections in digits passed
					in this command and the sections in primary or
					backup address. This paramter is mandatory.

					MASK DEFINITIONS

					Mnemonic	Function
					----------------------------------
					- 		Ignore

					/		Separator used to split the mask
							into sections.

					K		Retain the original dialed digits
							of this section in the translated
							digits.

					R		Replace the original dialed digits
							of this section with the same
							section from primary or backup
							address in the translated digits.

	<address-indicator>	-	The address indicator is the first field in a SCCP
					Party Address (called/calling) and is one octet in
					length. Its function is to indicate which
					information elements are present so that the
					address can be interpreted. In other words, it
					indicates the type of addressing information that
					is to be found in the address field. The
					addressing information from the original global
					title is then compared with the passed address
					information to match the rule.

					SCCP ADDRESS INDICATOR
					--------------------------------
					| 8 | 7 | 6 | 5 | 4 |3 | 2 | 1 |
					--------------------------------

					Bit '1'     : PC Indicator
						      (1 = included)

					Bit '2'     : SSN Indicator
						      (1 = included)

					Bit '3 - 6' : GT Indicator
						      (0000 = GT not included)
						      (0001 = GT includes
							      Nature of Address)
						      (0010 = GT includes
							      Translation Type)
						      (0011 = GT includes
							      Translation Type,
							      Numbering Plan and
							      Encoding Scheme)
						      (0100 = GT includes
							      Translation Type,
							      Numbering Plan and
							      Encoding Scheme and
							      Nature of Address)

					Bit '7'     : Routing Indicator
						      (0 = Route on GT,
						      1 = Route on PC + SSN)

					Bit '8'     : Reserved for National use.

                    Only GT Indicator is used in the current implementation.
                    A Rule matches to an original address only if GT Indicator
                    from address-indicator is the same in a rule and in an
                    original address. GT Indicator for ITU-T network that is
                    mostly used is - 0100 (GT includes Translation Type,
                    Numbering Plan and Encoding Scheme and Nature of Address).
                    If you also use 0100 - use digital value for it - 16.
                    Even when SCCP stack works in ANSI mode Address Indicator
                    value for CLI and GUI must have values that we use for
                    ITU-T mode.

	<point-code>		-	MTP Signaling Point Code. This is ignored if
					Bit '0' of address-indicator is not set.
                    This parameter is not used in currentimplemetation and
                    can be set to "0".

	<subsystem-number>	-	This is ignored if Bit '1' of address-indicator is
					not set.
                    This parameter is not used in currentimplemetation and
                    can be set to "0".

	<translation-type>	-	This is ignored if GT Indicator is 0000 or 0001.

					TRANSLATION TYPE VALUES

					Value		Description
					----------------------------------
					0		Unknown

					1  - 63		International Service

					64 - 127	Spare

					128 - 254	National Network Specific

					255		Reserved for Expansion

                    This paramter is mandatory.
                    A Rule matches to an original address only if a value of
                    this parameter is the same in a rule and in an original
                    address. Values are compared only if GT type contains this
                    parameter (see GT Indicator description in
                    <address-indicator> parameter).
                    Most used values:
                    0 - translation-type - Unknown

	<numbering-plan>	-	The Number Plan (NP) field specifies the numbering
					plan which the address information follows. This
					is ignored if GT Indicator is 0000, 0001 or 0010.

					NUMBER PLAN VALUES

					Value		Description
					----------------------------------
					0		Unknown

					1		ISDN/Telephony Number Plan
							(Recommendations E.163 and E.164)

					2		Generic Numbering Plan

					3		Data Numbering Plan
							(Recommendations X.121)

					4		Telex Numbering Plan
							(Recommendations F.69)

					5		Maritime Mobile Numbering Plan
							(Recommendations E.210, E.211)

					6		Land Mobile Numbering Plan
							(Recommendations E.212)

					7		ISDN/Mobile Numbering Plan
							(Recommendations E.214)

					8 to 13		Spare

					14		Private Network or
							Network-Specific Numbering Plan

					15		Reserved

                    This paramter is mandatory.
                    A Rule matches to an original address only if a value of
                    this parameter is the same in a rule and in an original
                    address. Values are compared only if GT type contains this
                    parameter (see GT Indicator description in
                    <address-indicator> parameter).
                    Most used values:
                    1 - numbering-plan - ISDN/telephony

	<nature-of-address>	-	The Nature of Address Indicator (NAI) field
					defines the address range for a specific numbering
					plan. This is only used if GT Indicator is 0100.

					NAI VALUES

					Value		Description
					----------------------------------
					0		Unknown

					1		Subscriber Number

					2		Reserved for National use

					3		National Significant Number

					4		International Number

					5 to 127	Spare

                    This paramter is mandatory.
                    A Rule matches to an original address only if a value of
                    this parameter is the same in a rule and in an original
                    address. Values are compared only if GT type contains this
                    parameter (see GT Indicator description in
                    <address-indicator> parameter).
                    Most used values:
                    4 - nature-of-address - International

	<digits>		-	Specifies the string of digits divided into
					subsections using separator '/' depending on if
					the mask contains separator or not. The dialed
					digits should match with theses digits as per the
					rule specified below:

					DIGIT PATTERN

					Value		Description
					----------------------------------
					-		padding - ignored

					*		wildcard - matches any number of
							digits

					?		wildcard - matches exactly one
							digit

					/		separator used to split the digit
							pattern into sections.
							Each section can be processed
							differently as specified
							by the mask parameter.

                    This parameter is mandatory. It should contain the same
                    subsections count as the rule mask has.

	<ruleType>		-	Takes one of the following values defined below.

					RULE TYPE VALUES

					Value		Description
					----------------------------------
					solitary	Only one (primary) address is used
							for routing.
							(<backup-address-id> may be missed
							in this case).

					dominant	Both primary and backup
							addresses are used and mandatory.
							If both the addresses are
							available, the primary address is
							used for routing.

					loadshared	Both primary and backup
							addresses are used and mandatory.
							If both the addresses are
							available, either primary or
							backup address is used for
							routing.
							The <loadsharing-algorithm> should
							be configured in this case.

					broadcast	Both primary and backup addresses
							are used and are mandatory. All
							messages are routed to both
							addresses.

	<primary-address-id>	-	Identifies the SCCP Address used as the primary
					translation.

	Optional Parameters

	<backup-address-id>	-	Identifies the SCCP Address used as the backup
					translation in case the pointcode specified by the
					primary address is not available. Backup address
					is used if <ruleType> is not "solitary".

	<loadsharing-algorithm>	-	This parameter is mandatory if <ruleType> is
					"loadshared". The Loadsharing algorithm is
					configured here. Possible values of the parameter
					are:

					LOAD SHARING ALGORITHM VALUES

					Value		Description
					----------------------------------
					bit4 		if( (SLS & 0x10) == 0 )
							<route to primary> else
							<route to backup>

							This algorithm is the best if all
							traffic is local (mobicents stack)
							originated

					bit3		if( (SLS & 0x08) == 0 )
							<route to primary> else
							<route to backup>
							This algorithm can be used if not
							all traffic is local
							(mobicents stack) originated.
							But only 8 links are acceptable in
							both linksets.

	<new-callingPartyAddress-id>
				-	This address will replace the
					callingPartyAddresses of messages that fit a Rule.

	<originationType>	-	Takes one of the following values defined below.
					If the parameter is not defined, rule applies to
					all messages regardless of their origination.

					ORIGINATION TYPE VALUES

					Value			Description
					-------------------------------------
					localOriginated		If this parameter is
								"localOriginated", then a
								rule applies only for
								messages originating from
								local SCCP users
								(for example a local
								TCAP stack).

					remoteOriginated	If this parameter is
								"remoteOriginated", then a
								rule applies only for
								messages originating from
								SS7 network and not for
								messages originating from
								local SCCP users.

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

    <networkId>     - A digital parameter that means to which virtual SS7 network
                    belongs a Rule. If this parameter is skipped - networkId will
                    be set to "0" when a Rule creation.
                    Refer <xref linkend="design_multitenancy"/>.
]]></screen>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_rule_delete">
		<title>Delete a Rule</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rule_delete_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can delete a Rule by issuing the command <command>sccp rule delete</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp rule delete

SYNOPSIS
	sccp rule delete <id> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to remove a previously defined Rule.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>			-	The identifier of the Rule that is being deleted.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp rule delete 1

	The above command will delete the Rule identified by the number '1'.
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rule_delete_gui">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
			<procedure>
				<title>Delete a Rule using GUI</title>
				<step><para>Navigate to the 'Rules' tab in the SCCP Management Unit window and locate the row corresponding to the Rule you wish to delete.</para></step>
				<step><para>In the row corresponding to the identified Rule, click on the red 'x' button in the actions column to delete that Rule.</para></step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	</section>


<section id="managing_sccp_rsp_show">
		<title>View all configured Remote Signaling Points (RSP)</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rsp_show_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can view the details of all configured Remote Signaling Points by issuing the command <command>sccp rsp show</command> as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp rsp show

SYNOPSIS
	sccp rsp show <id> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to view the details of all configured Remote Signaling Points.

	If an <id> is specified in the command, it will only display the details of the
	Remote Signaling Point identified by the value of the 'id' specified.

PARAMETERS

	Optional Parameters

	<id>		-	The id of the Remote Signaling Point whose details are
				to be displayed. If this parameter is not specified, the
				details of all configured Remote Signaling Points will be
				displayed.

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rsp_show_GUI">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
<para>Navigate to the specific SCCP Management unit and switch to the 'RSP' tab. Here you can view a list of all the configured Remote Signaling Pointcodes. Every correctly configured RSP will be displayed in a row along with the defined values.
</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_rsp_create">
		<title>Create a new Remote Signaling Pointcode</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rsp_create_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can create a new RSP by issuing the command <command>sccp rsp create</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp rsp create

SYNOPSIS
	sccp rsp create <id> <remote-spc> <rspc-flag> <mask>
	stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to define a new Remote Signaling Point. Each remote signaling
	point that SCCP can communicate with must be configured using this command.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>			-	A unique number to identify this
					Remote Signaling Point.

	<remote-spc>		-	The Remote Signaling Point

	<rspc-flag>		-	32 bit value. Not used for now.
					Reserved for future

	<mask>			-	32 bit value. Not used for now.
					Reserved for future

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp rsp create 1 6477 0 0
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rsp_create_gui">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
			<procedure>
				<title>Create a new RSP using GUI</title>
				<step><para>Navigate to the 'RSP' tab in the SCCP Management window and click on the 'Create RSP' button. This will launch a new pop-up 'Create Remote Signaling Pointcode'.
				</para></step>
				<step><para>In the 'Create Remote Signaling Pointcode' pop-up, add details of the new RSP being defined. You must ensure that you fill in all the mandatory parameters. For definition of these parameters, please refer to the description of the CLI command for the same in the preceding section.
				</para></step>
				<step><para>Verify the details entered and then click on the 'Create' button. A new RSP will be created with parameters as specified. If there is an error in creating the RSP then you will find the details of the error in the Management Console Log section below.</para></step>
				<step><para>Click on the 'Close' button to close the 'Create Remote Signaling Pointcode' pop-up.
				</para></step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_rsp_modify">
		<title>Modify a Remote Signaling Pointcode</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rsp_modify_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can modify the values of a RSP by issuing the command <command>sccp rsp modify</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp rsp modify

SYNOPSIS
	sccp rsp modify <id> <remote-spc> <rspc-flag> <mask> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to modify the values of a Remote Signaling Point previously
	defined.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>			-	Identifier of the Remote Signaling Point to be
					modified.

	<remote-spc>		-	The Remote Signaling Point

	<rspc-flag>		-	32 bit value. Not used for now.
					Reserved for future

	<mask>			-	32 bit value. Not used for now.
					Reserved for future

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.
]]></screen>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_rsp_delete">
		<title>Delete a Remote Signaling Pointcode</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rsp_delete_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can delete a RSP by issuing the command <command>sccp rsp delete</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp rsp delete

SYNOPSIS
	sccp rsp delete <id> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to delete a Remote Signaling Point.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>		-	The identifier of the Remote Signaling Point that is being
				deleted.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp rsp delete 1

	The above command will delete the Remote Signaling Point identified by the
	number '1'.
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rsp_delete_gui">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
			<procedure>
				<title>Delete a RSP using GUI</title>
				<step><para>Navigate to the 'RSP' tab in the SCCP Management Unit window and locate the row corresponding to the RSP you wish to delete.</para></step>
				<step><para>In the row corresponding to the identified RSP, click on the red 'x' button in the actions column to delete that RSP.</para></step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	</section>


<section id="managing_sccp_rss_show">
		<title>View all configured Remote Sub-Systems (RSS)</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rss_show_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can view the details of all configured Remote Sub-Systems by issuing the command <command>sccp rss show</command> as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp rss show

SYNOPSIS
	sccp rss show <id> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to view the details of all configured Remote Sub-Systems.
	If an <id> is specified in the command, it will only display the details of the
	Remote Sub-System identified by the value of the 'id' specified.

PARAMETERS

	Optional Parameters

	<id>		-	The id of the Remote Sub-System whose details are to be
				displayed. If this parameter is not specified, the details
				of all configured Remote Sub-Systems will be displayed.

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rss_show_GUI">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
<para>Navigate to the specific SCCP Management unit and switch to the 'RSS' tab. Here you can view a list of all the configured Remote Sub-Systems. Every correctly configured RSS will be displayed in a row along with the defined values.
</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_rss_create">
		<title>Create a new Remote Sub-System</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rss_create_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can create a new RSS by issuing the command <command>sccp rss create</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp rss create

SYNOPSIS
	sccp rss create <id> <remote-spc> <remote-ssn> <rss-flag>
	<mark-prohibited-when-spc-resuming> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to define a new Remote Sub-System. Each Remote Sub-System
	that SCCP can communicate with must be configured using this command. You must
	ensure that the Remote Signaling Point is configured prior to issuing this
	command.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>			-	A unique number to identify this Remote
					Sub-System.

	<remote-spc>		-	The Remote Signaling Point where this Remote
					Sub-System is being deployed.

	<remote-ssn>		-	The Remote Sub-System number.

	<rss-flag>		-	32 bit value. Not used for now.
					Reserved for future.

	Optional Parameters

	<mark-prohibited-when-spc-resuming>
				-	Possible value: prohibitedWhenSpcResuming.
					When this parameter is specified, the configured
					subsystem is marked as prohibited when its
					corresponding signaling point code has been
					resumed.

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp rss create 1 6477 8 0 prohibitedWhenSpcResuming
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rss_create_gui">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
			<procedure>
				<title>Create a new RSS using GUI</title>
				<step><para>Navigate to the 'RSS' tab in the SCCP Management window and click on the 'Create RSS' button. This will launch a new pop-up 'Create Remote Sub-System'.
				</para></step>
				<step><para>In the 'Create Remote Sub-System' pop-up, add details of the new RSS being defined. You must ensure that you fill in all the mandatory parameters. For definition of these parameters, please refer to the description of the CLI command for the same in the preceding section.
				</para></step>
				<step><para>Verify the details entered and then click on the 'Create' button. A new RSS will be created with parameters as specified. If there is an error in creating the RSS then you will find the details of the error in the Management Console Log section below.</para></step>
				<step><para>Click on the 'Close' button to close the 'Create Remote Sub-System' pop-up.
				</para></step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_rss_modify">
		<title>Modify a Remote Signaling Sub-System</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rss_modify_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can modify the values of a RSS by issuing the command <command>sccp rss modify</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp rss modify

SYNOPSIS
	sccp rss modify <id> <remote-spc> <remote-ssn> <rss-flag>
	<mark-prohibited-when-spc-resuming> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to modify the values of a Remote Sub-System previously
	defined.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>			-	Identifier of the Remote Sub-System to be
					modified.

	<remote-spc>		-	The Remote Signaling Point where this Remote
					Sub-System is deployed.

	<remote-ssn>		-	The Remote Sub-System number.

	<rss-flag>		-	32 bit value. Not used for now.
					Reserved for future.

	Optional Parameters

	<mark-prohibited-when-spc-resuming>
				-	Possible value: prohibitedWhenSpcResuming.
					When this parameter is specified, the configured
					subsystem is marked as prohibited when its
					corresponding signaling point code has been
					resumed.

	Optional Parameters

	<mark-prohibited-when-spc-resuming>
				-	Possible value: prohibitedWhenSpcResuming.
					When this parameter is specified, the configured
					subsystem is marked as prohibited when its
					corresponding signaling point code has been
					resumed.

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.
]]></screen>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_rss_delete">
		<title>Delete a Remote Signaling Sub-System</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rss_delete_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can delete a RSS by issuing the command <command>sccp rss delete</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp rss delete

SYNOPSIS
	sccp rss delete <id> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to delete a Remote Sub-System.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>		-	The identifier of the Remote Sub-System that is being
				deleted.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp rss delete 1

	The above command will delete the Remote Sub-System identified by the number '1'.
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_rss_delete_gui">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
			<procedure>
				<title>Delete a RSS using GUI</title>
				<step><para>Navigate to the 'RSS' tab in the SCCP Management Unit window and locate the row corresponding to the RSS you wish to delete.</para></step>
				<step><para>In the row corresponding to the identified RSS, click on the red 'x' button in the actions column to delete that RSS.</para></step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	</section>

<section id="managing_sccp_lmr_show">
		<title>View all configured Long Message Rules (LMR)</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_lmr_show_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can view the details of all configured Long Message Rules by issuing the command <command>sccp lmr show</command> as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp lmr show

SYNOPSIS
	sccp lmr show <id> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to view the details of all configured Long Message Rules.
	If an <id> is specified in the command, it will only display the details of the
	Long Message Rule identified by the value of the 'id' specified.

PARAMETERS

	Optional Parameters

	<id>			-	The id of the Long Message Rule whose details are to be
					displayed. If this parameter is not specified, the details
					of all configured Long Message Rules will be displayed.

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_lmr_show_GUI">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
<para>Navigate to the specific SCCP Management unit and switch to the 'LMR' tab. Here you can view a list of all the configured Long Message Rules. Every correctly configured LMR will be displayed in a row along with the defined values.
</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_lmr_create">
		<title>Create a new Long Message Rule</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_lmr_create_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can create a new LMR by issuing the command <command>sccp lmr create</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp lmr create

SYNOPSIS
	sccp lmr create <id> <first-spc> <last-spc> <long-message-rule-type>
	stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to define a new Long Message Rule. Long message rules specify
	which message types (UDT/XUDT/LUDT) will be used for outgoing message encoding
	depends on dpc. If long message rules are not configured only UDT messages
	will be used.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>			-	A unique number to identify this
					Long Message Rule.

	<first-spc>		-	The first value of the remote signaling
					point code range, for which this Long message Rule
					will apply.

	<last-spc>		-	The last value of the remote signaling point code
					range. If Long message rule specifies a single
					signaling point code, this value must be equal to
					first-spc.

	<long-message-rule-type>-	Message types used for the remote signaling
					point codes range.
					Possible values : udt, xudt and ludt.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp lmr create 1 201 201 xudt

	sccp lmr create 2 230 239 udt

]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_lmr_create_gui">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
			<procedure>
				<title>Create a new LMR using GUI</title>
				<step><para>Navigate to the 'LMR' tab in the SCCP Management window and click on the 'Create LMR' button. This will launch a new pop-up 'Create Long Message Rule'.
				</para></step>
				<step><para>In the 'Create Long Message Rule' pop-up, add details of the new LMR being defined. You must ensure that you fill in all the mandatory parameters. For definition of these parameters, please refer to the description of the CLI command for the same in the preceding section.
				</para></step>
				<step><para>Verify the details entered and then click on the 'Create' button. A new LMR will be created with parameters as specified. If there is an error in creating the LMR then you will find the details of the error in the Management Console Log section below.</para></step>
				<step><para>Click on the 'Close' button to close the 'Create Long Message Rule' pop-up.
				</para></step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_lmr_modify">
		<title>Modify a Long Message Rule</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_lmr_modify_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can modify the values of a LMR by issuing the command <command>sccp lmr modify</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp lmr modify

SYNOPSIS
	sccp lmr modify <id> <first-spc> <last-spc> <long-message-rule-type>
	stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to modify the values of a Long Message Rule previously
	defined.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>			-	Identifier of the Long Message Rule to be
					modified.

	<first-spc>		-	The first value of the remote signaling
					point code range, for which this Long message Rule
					will apply.

	<last-spc>		-	The last value of the remote signaling point code
					range. If Long message rule specifies a single
					signaling point code, this value must be equal to
					first-spc.

	<long-message-rule-type>-	Message types used for the remote signaling point
					codes range.
					Possible values : udt, xudt and ludt.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.
]]></screen>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_lmr_delete">
		<title>Delete a Long Message Rule</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_lmr_delete_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can delete a LMR by issuing the command <command>sccp lmr delete</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp lmr delete

SYNOPSIS
	sccp lmr delete <id> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to delete a Long Message Rule.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>		-	The identifier of the Long Message Rule that is being
				deleted.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp lmr delete 1

	The above command will delete the Long Message Rule identified by the number '1'.
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_lmr_delete_gui">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
			<procedure>
				<title>Delete a Long Message Rule using GUI</title>
				<step><para>Navigate to the 'LMR' tab in the SCCP Management Unit window and locate the row corresponding to the LMR you wish to delete.</para></step>
				<step><para>In the row corresponding to the identified LMR, click on the red 'x' button in the actions column to delete that LMR.</para></step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	</section>
<section id="managing_sccp_csp_show">
		<title>View all configured Concerned Signaling Point Codes (CSP)</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_csp_show_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can view the details of all configured Concerned Signaling Point Codes by issuing the command <command>sccp csp show</command> as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp csp show

SYNOPSIS
	sccp csp show <id> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to view the details of all configured Concerned Signaling
	Point Codes. If an <id> is specified in the command, it will only display the
	details of the Concerned Signaling Point Code identified by the value of the 'id'
	specified.

PARAMETERS

	Optional Parameters

	<id>			-	The id of the Concerned Signaling Point Code whose details
					are to be displayed. If this parameter is not specified,
					the details of all configured Concerned Signaling Point
					Codes will be displayed.

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_csp_show_GUI">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
<para>Navigate to the specific SCCP Management unit and switch to the 'CSP' tab. Here you can view a list of all the configured Concerned Signaling Point Code. Every correctly configured CSP will be displayed in a row along with the defined values.
</para>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_csp_create">
		<title>Create a new Concerned Signaling Point Code</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_csp_create_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can create a new CSP by issuing the command <command>sccp csp create</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp csp create

SYNOPSIS
	sccp csp create <id> <spc> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to define a new Concerned Signaling Point Code. Concerned
	signaling point codes define a DPC list that will be notified when local SSN is
	registered (SSA messages) or unregistered (SSP messages).

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>			-	A unique number to identify this
					Concerned Signaling Point Code.

	<spc>			-	The Remote Signaling Point Code,
					which will be notified.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.


EXAMPLES
	sccp csp create 1 201

	sccp csp create 2 202

]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_csp_create_gui">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
			<procedure>
				<title>Create a new CSP using GUI</title>
				<step><para>Navigate to the 'CSP' tab in the SCCP Management window and click on the 'Create CSP' button. This will launch a new pop-up 'Create Concerned Signaling Point Code'.
				</para></step>
				<step><para>In the 'Create Concerned Signaling Point Code' pop-up, add details of the new CSP being defined. You must ensure that you fill in all the mandatory parameters. For definition of these parameters, please refer to the description of the CLI command for the same in the preceding section.
				</para></step>
				<step><para>Verify the details entered and then click on the 'Create' button. A new CSP will be created with parameters as specified. If there is an error in creating the CSP then you will find the details of the error in the Management Console Log section below.</para></step>
				<step><para>Click on the 'Close' button to close the 'Create Concerned Signaling Point Code' pop-up.
				</para></step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_csp_modify">
		<title>Modify a Concerned Signaling Point Code</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_csp_modify_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can modify the values of a CSP by issuing the command <command>sccp csp modify</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp csp modify

SYNOPSIS
	sccp csp modify <id> <spc> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to modify the values of a Concerned Signaling Point Code
	previously defined.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>			-	Identifier of the Concerned Signaling Point Code
					to be modified.

	<spc>			-	The Remote Signaling Point Code, which will be
					notified.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.
]]></screen>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="managing_sccp_csp_delete">
		<title>Delete a Concerned Signaling Point Code</title>
		<section id="managing_sccp_csp_delete_cli">
		<title>Using CLI</title>
<para>You can delete a CSP by issuing the command <command>sccp csp delete</command> with appropriate parameters as described below:
		</para>
<screen><![CDATA[
Name
	sccp csp delete

SYNOPSIS
	sccp csp delete <id> stackname <stack-name>

DESCRIPTION
	This command is used to delete a Concerned Signaling Point Code.

PARAMETERS

	Standard Parameters

	<id>		-	The identifier of the Concerned Signaling Point Code
				that is being deleted.

	Optional Parameters

	<stack-name>	-	Name of the stack on which this command is executed.
					If not passed, the first stack configured in ShellExecutor
					will be used.

EXAMPLES
	sccp csp delete 1

	The above command will delete the Concerned Signaling Point Code identified by the
	number '1'.
]]></screen>
		</section>
		<section id="managing_sccp_csp_delete_gui">
		<title>Using GUI</title>
			<procedure>
				<title>Delete a Concerned Signaling Point Code using GUI</title>
				<step><para>Navigate to the 'CSP' tab in the SCCP Management Unit window and locate the row corresponding to the CSP you wish to delete.</para></step>
				<step><para>In the row corresponding to the identified CSP, click on the red 'x' button in the actions column to delete that CSP.</para></step>
			</procedure>
		</section>
	</section>
</section>
