<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "SS7_Stack_User_Guide.ent">%BOOK_ENTITIES;]>

<chapter id="introduction">

	<title>Introduction
		to &THIS.PLATFORM;  &THIS.APPLICATION;
	</title>
	<!-- POssibly this should go into abstract ? -->
	<important><para>For a better understanding of this chapter please read ITU-T Q.771 to Q.774.</para> </important>
		<para>TCAP supports the exchange of non-circuit related data between
			applications across the SS7 network, using the SCCP connectionless
			service. Queries and responses sent between SSPs and SCPs are carried
			in TCAP messages.
    </para>
    <para>For example, an SSP sends a TCAP query to determine
			the routing number associated with a dialed 800/888 number and to
			check the personal identification number (PIN) of a calling card
			user. In mobile networks (IS-41 and GSM), TCAP carries Mobile
			Application Part (MAP) messages sent between mobile switches and
			databases to support user authentication, equipment identification,
			and roaming.</para>
			<para>
			TCAP messages and parameters are refered as <literal>primitives</literal>. Primitives are exchanged 
				within logical entities called dialogs. There are two types of dialogs:
      </para>
				<variablelist>
          <varlistentry>
            <term>Unstructured</term>
            <listitem>
						<para>Short lived. It is created only to deliver a single message (<literal>Unstructured primitive</literal>), after the delivery dialog is invalidated. </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
					<varlistentry>
            <term>Structured</term>
            <listitem>
              <para>Long lived. It is created when the exchange starts and lives until it is terminated. </para>
            </listitem>
          </varlistentry>
				</variablelist>
			<para>
				TCAP defines the following message types:
			</para>			
			<variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Unstructured</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Creates an Unstructured dialog. An Unstructured dialog is invalidated once this message is either sent or consumed. It is meant for messages that don't require an answer or interaction.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Begin</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Message sent to begin Structured dialog. It carries context information for the dialog being created.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Continue</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Continues a Structured dialog.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>End</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Ends a Structured dialog in a graceful way.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>Abort</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Aborts the Structured dialog.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
			<para>TCAP messages convey two types of information:</para>
			<variablelist>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>components</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Elements that carry information on the requested operation, their status and result.
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
        <varlistentry>
          <term>dialog related</term>
          <listitem>
            <para>
            Dialog context (application context name) and application specific information (user information).
            </para>
          </listitem>
        </varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
	

</chapter>
