<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "SS7_Stack_User_Guide.ent">%BOOK_ENTITIES;]>

<chapter id="introduction">

	<title>Introduction
		to &THIS.PLATFORM;  &THIS.APPLICATION;
	</title>
	<para>
		Common Channel Signaling System No. 7 (i.e., <acronym>SS7</acronym> or <acronym>C7</acronym>) is a
		global
		standard for telecommunications defined by the
		<ulink url="http://www.voip-info.org/wiki/view/ITU">International
			Telecommunication Union (<acronym></acronym>ITU)
			Telecommunication Standardization Sector
			(ITU-T)</ulink>
		. The standard defines the procedures and protocol by which
		network
		elements in the public switched telephone network (<acronym>PSTN</acronym>)
		)
		exchange information over a digital signaling network to effect
		wireless (cellular) and wireline call setup, routing and control. The
		ITU definition of SS7 allows for national variants such as the
		American National Standards Institute (ANSI) and Bell Communications
		Research (Telcordia Technologies) standards used in North America and
		the European Telecommunications Standards Institute (
		<ulink url="http://www.voip-info.org/wiki/view/ETSI">ETSI</ulink>
		) standard
		used in Europe.
	</para>
	<para>
		The hardware and software functions of the <acronym>SS7</acronym> protocol are divided
		into
		functional abstractions called "levels". These levels map loosely
		to
		the Open Systems Interconnect (<acronym>OSI</acronym>) 7-layer model defined by the
		<ulink url="http://www.iso.ch/">International Standards Organization (ISO)</ulink>
		.
	</para>
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata width="300px" align="center" fileref="images/ss7-fig3.gif"
				format="GIF" />
		</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>SS7 Stack overview
			</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
	<section>
		<title>Time Division Multiplexing</title>
		<para>
			In circuit switched networks such as the Public Switched Telephone
			Network (<acronym>PSTN</acronym>) there exists the need to transmit multiple
			subscribers’ calls along the same transmission medium. To accomplish
			this, network designers make use of <acronym>TDM</acronym>. <acronym>TDM</acronym> allows switches to
			create channels, also known as tributaries, within a transmission
			stream. A standard DS0 voice signal has a data bit rate of 64 kbit/s,
			determined using Nyquist’s sampling criterion. <acronym>TDM</acronym> takes frames of
			the voice signals and multiplexes them into a <acronym>TDM</acronym> frame which runs at
			a higher bandwidth. So if the <acronym>TDM</acronym> frame consists of n voice frames,
			the bandwidth will be n*64 kbit/s.
			Each voice sample timeslot in the <acronym>TDM</acronym> frame is called a channel . In
			European systems, <acronym>TDM</acronym> frames contain 30 digital voice channels, and
			in American systems, they contain 24 channels. Both standards also
			contain extra bits (or bit timeslots) for signalling (SS7) and
			synchronisation bits.
			Multiplexing more than 24 or 30 digital voice channels is called higher order
			multiplexing. Higher order multiplexing is accomplished by
			multiplexing the standard <acronym>TDM</acronym> frames.For example, a European 120
			channel <acronym>TDM</acronym> frame is formed by multiplexing four standard 30 channel
			<acronym>TDM</acronym> frames.At each higher order multiplex, four <acronym>TDM</acronym> frames from the
			immediate lower order are combined, creating multiplexes with a
			bandwidth of n x 64 kbit/s, where n = 120, 480, 1920, etc.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>MTP Introduction</title>
		<para>The Message Transfer Part (MTP) is divided into three levels.
			The lowest level, MTP Level 1, is equivalent to the OSI Physical
			Layer. MTP Level 1 defines the physical, electrical, and functional
			characteristics of the digital signaling link. Physical interfaces
			defined include E-1 (2048 kb/s; 32 64 kb/s channels), DS-1 (1544
			kb/s; 24 64kb/s channels), V.35 (64 kb/s), DS-0 (64 kb/s), and DS-0A
			(56 kb/s).
			MTP Level 2 ensures accurate end-to-end transmission of a message across
			a signaling link. Level 2 implements flow control, message sequence
			validation, and error checking. When an error occurs on a signaling
			link, the message (or set of messages) is retransmitted. MTP Level 2
			is equivalent to the OSI Data Link Layer.
			MTP Level 3 provides message routing between signaling points in the SS7
			network. MTP Level 3 re-routes traffic away from failed links and
			signaling points and controls traffic when congestion occurs. MTP
			Level 3 is equivalent to the OSI Network Layer.</para>
	</section>

</chapter>