<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "SS7_Stack_User_Guide.ent">%BOOK_ENTITIES;]>

<chapter id="introduction">

	<title>Introduction
		to &THIS.PLATFORM;  &THIS.APPLICATION;
	</title>
	<important>
       		<para>Spaces where introduced in in some tables and code listings to ensure proper page render.</para>
	</important>
	<para>
		Common Channel Signaling System No. 7 (i.e., <acronym>SS7</acronym> or <acronym>C7</acronym>) is a
		global
		standard for telecommunications defined by the
		<ulink url="http://www.voip-info.org/wiki/view/ITU">International
			Telecommunication Union (<acronym></acronym>ITU)
			Telecommunication Standardization Sector
			(ITU-T)</ulink>
		. The standard defines the procedures and protocol by which
		network
		elements in the public switched telephone network (<acronym>PSTN</acronym>)
		)
		exchange information over a digital signaling network to effect
		wireless (cellular) and wireline call setup, routing and control. The
		ITU definition of SS7 allows for national variants such as the
		American National Standards Institute (ANSI) and Bell Communications
		Research (Telcordia Technologies) standards used in North America and
		the European Telecommunications Standards Institute (
		<ulink url="http://www.voip-info.org/wiki/view/ETSI">ETSI</ulink>
		) standard
		used in Europe.
	</para>
	<para>
		The hardware and software functions of the <acronym>SS7</acronym> protocol are divided
		into
		functional abstractions called "levels". These levels map loosely
		to
		the Open Systems Interconnect (<acronym>OSI</acronym>) 7-layer model defined by the
		<ulink url="http://www.iso.ch/">International Standards Organization (ISO)</ulink>
		.
	</para>
	<mediaobject>
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata width="300px" align="center" fileref="images/ss7-fig3.gif"
				format="GIF" />
		</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>SS7 Stack overview
			</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
	<para>
		&THIS.PLATFORM;  &THIS.APPLICATION; is software based SS7 protocol implementation providing Level 2 and above. 
		The &THIS.PLATFORM;  &THIS.APPLICATION; is a platform in the sense that it does not provide the application itself but rather allows users
to build the application
	</para>	
	<section>
		<title>Time Division Multiplexing</title>
		<para>
			In circuit switched networks such as the Public Switched Telephone
			Network (<acronym>PSTN</acronym>) there exists the need to transmit multiple
			subscribers’ calls along the same transmission medium. To accomplish
			this, network designers make use of <acronym>TDM</acronym>. <acronym>TDM</acronym> allows switches to
			create channels, also known as tributaries, within a transmission
			stream. A standard DS0 voice signal has a data bit rate of 64 kbit/s,
			determined using Nyquist’s sampling criterion. <acronym>TDM</acronym> takes frames of
			the voice signals and multiplexes them into a <acronym>TDM</acronym> frame which runs at
			a higher bandwidth. So if the <acronym>TDM</acronym> frame consists of n voice frames,
			the bandwidth will be n*64 kbit/s.
			Each voice sample timeslot in the <acronym>TDM</acronym> frame is called a channel . In
			European systems, <acronym>TDM</acronym> frames contain 30 digital voice channels, and
			in American systems, they contain 24 channels. Both standards also
			contain extra bits (or bit timeslots) for signalling (SS7) and
			synchronisation bits.
			Multiplexing more than 24 or 30 digital voice channels is called higher order
			multiplexing. Higher order multiplexing is accomplished by
			multiplexing the standard <acronym>TDM</acronym> frames.For example, a European 120
			channel <acronym>TDM</acronym> frame is formed by multiplexing four standard 30 channel
			<acronym>TDM</acronym> frames.At each higher order multiplex, four <acronym>TDM</acronym> frames from the
			immediate lower order are combined, creating multiplexes with a
			bandwidth of n x 64 kbit/s, where n = 120, 480, 1920, etc.
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>The Basics</title>
		<important>
			<para>Be aware, &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; is subject to changes as it is under active development!
			</para>
		</important>
		<para>The &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; is logically divided into two sections. 
		The lower section includes SS7 Level 3 and below. The lower section is influenced by type of SS7 hardware (Level 1) used.
		</para>
		<para>
		The upper section includes SS7 Level 4 and above.
		This logical division is widely based on flexibility of &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; to allow usage of M3UA or any SS7 hardware 
		available in the market and yet &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; Level 4 and above remains the same. 
		</para>
		
		<para>
			&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; also includes support for M3UA (SIGTRAN)
		</para>
		
		<important>
			<para>If you use &THIS.PLATFORM; M3UA stack, you have to use JDK 7 to run the stack as well as to compile source code. M3UA leverages Java SCTP which is available only from JDK 7.</para>
		</important>
	</section>
	<section>
		<title>Design</title>
		<para>
			&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; uses the abstraction layer at level 3, such that this abstraction layer exposes same API to layer 4
			while it can be configured to interact with any SS7 cards via card specific module or &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; M3UA layer.
		</para>
		<para>
			Below diagram gives further detail on how this abstraction is achieved.
		</para>
		<para>
			&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; is designed such that it can be used in any container like JBoss Application Server or it can
			be also fired as standalone Java Application. 
		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>