<?xml version='1.0'?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "SS7_Stack_User_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>

<chapter
	id="design_overview">

	<title>The Basics of &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION;</title>
	<warning>
		<para>Be aware that &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; is subject to change since it is currently under active development!
		</para>
	</warning>
<section id="logical_divisions">
<title>Logical Divisions</title>	
	<para>The &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; is logically divided into two sections - lower and upper. The lower section provides implementation for SS7 Level 2 and Level 3. This section is therefore influenced by the type of SS7 hardware (Level 1) used. The upper section provides implementation for SS7 Level 4 and above. This logical division offers great flexibility where hardware is concerned. Irrespective of the type of hardware used in the lower section, &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; Level 4 and above remains the same. 
	</para>
	
	<para>
		&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; gives you the flexibility to install and use the Levels 2,3 and 4 in the same JVM and machine where SS7 Hardware (Level 1) is installed. Alternately, you can also install Level 1,2 and 3 in one machine and install Level 4 on a separate machine. In the second scenario, <literal>M3UA</literal> over <literal>SCTP</literal> 
		is used for communication between Level 3 and Level 4 (on different machines) and this is referred to as &THIS.PLATFORM; Signaling Gateway. The figures below illustrate the above 2 scenarios.
	</para>
	<para>
	Scenario 1: The complete &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; is installed in one machine.
	<mediaobject id="ss7_stack_same_machine">
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata
				width="300px"
				align="center"
				fileref="images/SS7StackSimple.jpg"
				format="JPG" />
		</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION;</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
	</para>
	<para>
	Scenario 2: &THIS.PLATFORM; Signaling Gateway - Level 3 and below are installed on one machine and Level 4 is installed on a different machine. 
	</para>
	<mediaobject id="signaling_gateway">
		<imageobject>
			<imagedata
				align="center"
				fileref="images/MobicentsSgw.jpg"
				format="JPG" />
		</imageobject>
		<caption>
			<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; Signaling Gateway</para>
		</caption>
	</mediaobject>
	
	<important>
		<para>If you use &THIS.PLATFORM; M3UA stack, you must use JDK 7 to run the stack as well as to compile the source code. M3UA leverages Java SCTP which is available only in JDK 7.</para>
	</important>
</section>	
<!-- Doesnt make sense 
	<para>
	 Apart from advantages mentioned in 
	</para>
		-->
<section id="functional_blocks">
	<title>Functional Blocks of &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION;</title>	
	<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION;
		consists of the following functional blocks:
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem><para>Shell Management Client</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>SS7 Service Elements</para></listitem>
			<listitem><para>Signaling Gateway</para></listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	</para>
		
		<section
		id="design_overview_shell">
		<title>Shell Management client</title>
				<para>
				  <literal>Shell</literal> is a Command Line Interface (CLI) tool that will allow you to manage different aspects of &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; in an interactive manner. 
					It connects to different instances of &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; which manages <literal>Linksets</literal>,
					<literal>SCCP</literal> resource, routing and <literal>M3UA</literal>. For detailed information please refer to:	<xref linkend="shell" />.
					Usually <literal>Shell</literal> will be invoked from remote machine(remote to <literal>Linksets</literal> and application protocols).

				</para>
				</section>
		<!--  	
		<varlistentry>
			<term>Application</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<literal>Application</literal>
					term encapsulates not only application level protocols(such as
					<literal>SCCP</literal>
					or
					<literal>ISUP</literal>
					) but also
					entities which make use of them(like
					<literal>SLEE RA &amp; Service</literal>
					)
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		-->
	

	<section
		id="design_overview_ss7_service">
		<title>SS7 Service Elements</title>
				<para>SS7 Service creates an instance of &THIS.PLATFORM; MAP Stack and binds the instance to JNDI name <literal>java:/mobicents/ss7/map</literal>. SS7 Service is a JMX based service deployed in JBoss Application Server. It hides the underlying details like whether Level 4 and above are connected to the &THIS.PLATFORM; Signaling Gateway via <literal>M3UA</literal> or if connected to the SS7 Hardware installed in the same machine as Level 4.</para>

		<para>
			The figure below depicts the elements that are deployed as part of SS7 Service.
		</para>

		<mediaobject
			id="ss7_service">
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata
					width="300px"
					align="center"
					fileref="images/ss7-design-overview3.jpg"
					format="PNG" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; Service Elements
				</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
		<para>SS7 Service Elements serve the following purposes:</para>
		<variablelist>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Expose protocol access points:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>Access points allow users to access lower layer protocols like <literal>MAP</literal> and interact with the <literal>SS7</literal> network through such protocols.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<varlistentry>
				<term>Expose management interface:</term>
				<listitem>
					<para><literal>Shell Executor</literal> allows the  <literal>Shell</literal> client to connect and issue commands.</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
		</variablelist>
		
		<para>Configuring the SS7 Service Elements is explained below in the section <xref linkend="configuring" /></para>
	</section>
	
	 
	 
	<section id="mobicents_signaling_gateway">
		<title>&THIS.PLATFORM; Signaling Gateway</title>

		<para>
			&THIS.PLATFORM; Signaling Gateway (SG) is a signaling agent that receives and sends Switched Circuit Network (SCN) 
			native signaling at the edge of the IP network. &THIS.PLATFORM; Signaling Gateway leverages MTP and &THIS.PLATFORM; <literal>M3UA</literal> Stack 
			explained in <xref linkend="mobicents_signaling_gateway_m3ua"/>.
		</para>
		
		<para>
			The figure below shows the components included in &THIS.PLATFORM; Signaling Gateway. Configuring the Signaling Gateway is explained in <xref linkend="configuring_sgw"/>.
		</para>
		<mediaobject
			id="sgw_elements">
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata
					width="300px"
					align="center"
					fileref="images/MobicentsSS7Gateway.jpg"
					format="JPG" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; Signaling Gateway Components
				</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>		
		
		<section id="mobicents_signaling_gateway_m3ua">
			<title>&THIS.PLATFORM; M3UA Stack</title>
	
			<para>
				<literal>M3UA</literal> is a client-server protocol supporting the transport of any SS7 MTP3-User signaling (e.g. <literal>ISUP</literal> and <literal>SCCP</literal> messages) over IP. <literal>M3UA</literal> is defined
				by the IETF SIGTRAN working group in RFC 4666. 
				&THIS.PLATFORM; M3UA Stack can be used on the Application Server side or on the Signaling Gateway side or can also be used in peer-to-peer mode IPSP. 
			</para>
		
			<note>
				<title>Note</title>
				<para>
					&THIS.PLATFORM; M3UA Stack uses Java SCTP layer which is only available from JDK 7 onwards.
				</para>
			</note>
					
			<section id="mobicents_signaling_gateway_m3ua_as">
				<title>&THIS.PLATFORM; M3UA Stack on the Application Server side</title>		
				<para>
					The figure below demonstrates the basic functionality of the &THIS.PLATFORM; M3UA Stack when configured as an Application Server (AS) 
					that will communicate with an External Signaling Gateway. 
				</para>
				<mediaobject
					id="m3ua_AS">
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							width="300px"
							align="center"
							fileref="images/M3UAAs.jpg"
							format="JPG" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; M3UA Stack configured as an AS
						</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>
					To use M3UA Stack as an AS, the Routing Context (RC) may not be known and is optional. Refer to Section <xref linkend="configuring_Rem_SGW"/> for help in configuring M3UA Stack 
					as an AS.
				</para>
			</section>
			
			<section id="mobicents_signaling_gateway_m3ua_SG">
				<title>&THIS.PLATFORM; M3UA Stack on the Signaling Gateway side</title>			
				<para>
					The figure below demonstrates the basic functionality of the &THIS.PLATFORM; M3UA Stack when configured as a Signaling Gateway (SG). 
					The &THIS.PLATFORM; Signaling Gateway provides the Nodal Interworking Function (NIF) that allows SS7 Signaling (SCCP/ISUP)
					to be inter-worked into the M3UA/IP Network.
					
				</para>
				<mediaobject
					id="m3ua_SGW">
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata
							width="300px"
							align="center"
							fileref="images/M3UASgw.jpg"
							format="JPG" />
					</imageobject>
					<caption>
						<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; M3UA Stack configured as a SG
						</para>
					</caption>
				</mediaobject>
				<para>
					&THIS.PLATFORM; M3UA Stack used on the SG side will share common point code with a set of M3UA Application Server. 
					M3UA stack on SG side can be configured as Loadbalance or Override traffic mode. It doesn't support Broadcast traffic mode. 
					See Section <xref linkend="configuring_sgw"/> for configuring M3UA Stack as SG. &THIS.PLATFORM; M3UA Stack used on SG side 
					doesn't support routing key management messages. The Routing Key should be provisioned statically using the management console.
				</para>	
			</section>	
		</section>
		</section>
		
		
	 </section>	 
	 
	 <!--  
	 <section id="mobicents_design_overview_ss7_service">
		<title>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; Usage</title>
		<para>The figure below depicts how &THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION; is used.
		</para>
		<mediaobject
			id="ss7_design_general_2">
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata
					width="300px"
					align="center"
					fileref="images/ss7-design-overview2.jpg"
					format="PNG" />
			</imageobject>
			<caption>
				<para>&THIS.PLATFORM; &THIS.APPLICATION;
					General Design
				</para>
			</caption>
		</mediaobject>
	 </section>
	 -->
</chapter>

